<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Video Games</string>

    <string-array name="gameTitles">
        <item>Minecraft</item>
        <item>Star Wars Jedi: Fallen Order</item>
        <item>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare</item>
        <item>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</item>
        <item>Death Stranding</item>
        <item>Red Dead Redemption 2</item>
        <item>Cyberpunk 2077</item>
        <item>NBA 2K20</item>
        <item>FIFA 20</item>
        <item>The Last of Us</item>
        <item>Grand Theft Auto V</item>
        <item>The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="gameImage">
        <item>@drawable/minecraft</item>
        <item>@drawable/starwarsjedi</item>
        <item>@drawable/callofduty</item>
        <item>@drawable/thelegendofzelda</item>
        <item>@drawable/deathstranding</item>
        <item>@drawable/reddead</item>
        <item>@drawable/cyberpunk</item>
        <item>@drawable/nba</item>
        <item>@drawable/fifa20</item>
        <item>@drawable/thelastofus</item>
        <item>@drawable/gtav</item>
        <item>@drawable/thewitcher3</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="gameRealeseDate">
        <item>May 17, 2009</item>
        <item>November 15, 2019</item>
        <item>October 25, 2019</item>
        <item>March 3, 2017</item>
        <item>November 8, 2019</item>
        <item>October 26, 2018</item>
        <item>April 16, 2020</item>
        <item>September 6, 2019</item>
        <item>September 24, 2019</item>
        <item>June 14, 2013</item>
        <item>September 17, 2013</item>
        <item>May 19, 2015</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="gameDescription">
        <item>Minecraft is a 3D sandbox game that has no specific goals to accomplish, allowing players a large amount of freedom in choosing how to play the game. However, there is an achievement system. Gameplay is in the first-person perspective by default, but players have the option for third-person perspective. The game world is composed of rough 3D objects—mainly cubes and fluids, and commonly called "blocks"—representing various materials, such as dirt, stone, ores, tree trunks, water, and lava. The core gameplay revolves around picking up and placing these objects. These blocks are arranged in a 3D grid, while players can move freely around the world. Players can "mine" blocks and then place them elsewhere, enabling them to build things.</item>
        <item>Players take control of Cal Kestis as he attempts to survive while being chased by the Empire, including the Inquisitor the Second Sister. Throughout his journey, young Cal will visit both new worlds and ones from Star Wars lore such as Kashyyyk, with the assistance of the Rebel extremist Saw Gerrera and his mentor Cere Junda. \nThe gameplay is that of an action adventure game, designed for players to "jump into a situation" and deal with it through "having a lightsaber and Force powers", not to utilise stealth elements to avoid combat. There is not an option to play a Dark Side path through the game. In combat, Force usage consists of three different abilities, Force "Push", Force "Pull", and Force "Slow".</item>
        <item>Modern Warfare\'s single-player campaign focuses on realism and feature tactically-based moral choices whereupon the player is evaluated and assigned a score at the end of each level; players have to quickly ascertain whether NPCs are a threat or not, such as a civilian woman who is believed to be reaching for a gun, but then simply grabs her baby from a crib. This collateral damage score, referred to as a threat assessment, is based on how many civilians the player injures or kills and ranges from rank A to F. Rewards are introduced to those who score higher. Character dialogue will differ depending on the choices the player makes in the game. Tactical decisions are also included, such as the player using a sniper rifle in a large environment to approach objectives in a non-linear order, and choosing to shoot out lights in favor of using night-vision goggles during breaching and clearing.</item>
        <item>Breath of the Wild is an action-adventure game set in an open world environment where players are tasked with exploring the kingdom of Hyrule while controlling Link. In terms of structure, Breath of the Wild encourages nonlinear gameplay, which is illustrated by the game\'s lack of defined entrances or exits to areas, scant instruction given to the player, and encouragement to explore freely. Breath of the Wild introduces a consistent physics engine to the Zelda series, letting players approach problems in different ways rather than trying to find a single solution. The game also integrates a "chemistry engine" that defines the physical properties of most objects and governs how they interact with the player and one another. For example, players may take advantage of the game\'s dynamic weather by throwing metal objects at enemies during thunderstorms to attract a lightning strike. However, the level of realism offered in the "chemistry engine" also means that players will equally attract an unavoidable fatal lightning strike if wearing any metal during thunderstorms. These design approaches result in a generally unstructured and interactive world that rewards experimentation and allows for nonlinear completion of the story.</item>
        <item>Death Stranding is an action game set in an open world, and also includes asynchronous online functions. Kojima compared the genre to how his earlier game Metal Gear – now considered to be a stealth game – was called an action game during its release because the stealth genre was not considered to exist at the time.\nThe player controls Sam Bridges, a porter for a company known as Bridges. The player is tasked with delivering supply cargo to various isolated cities known as KNOTs, while also connecting them to a communications system known as the Chiral Network. The player is evaluated by the company and recipients based on their performance (including via "likes" similar to social networks), including whether the cargo was delivered, and if it is intact among other factors. These merits are, in turn, used to level up the player\'s statistics (such as stability and weight capacity) and increase their standing with individual locations and characters (which can improve rewards). How cargo is packed by the player, and the overall weight being carried, can affect Sam\'s ability to navigate through the environments.</item>
        <item>Red Dead Redemption 2 is a Western-themed action-adventure game. Played from a first or third-person perspective, the game is set in an open-world environment featuring a fictionalized version of the Western, Midwestern and Southern United States. The game features both single-player and online multiplayer components, the latter released under Red Dead Online. For most of the game, the player controls outlaw Arthur Morgan, a member of the Van der Linde gang, as he completes numerous missions—linear scenarios with set objectives—to progress through the story; from the game\'s epilogue, the player controls John Marston. Outside of missions, the player may freely roam its interactive world. The player may engage in combat with enemies using melee attacks, firearms, throwables, or explosives. Combat has been refined from the game\'s predecessor, and notable new mechanics consist of dual-wielding and the ability to use a bow. Unlike the previous game, the player is granted the ability to swim.</item>
        <item>Cyberpunk 2077 is played in a first-person perspective as V, a mercenary whose voice, face, hairstyles, body type, body modifications, background, and clothing are customisable. V\'s clothing alters how interactions fare with non-player characters (NPCs), with whom they have the potential to form romantic and sexual relationships. Stat categories—Body, Intelligence, Reflexes, Technical, and Cool—are malleable depending on the character classes that players assume, which are NetRunner (hacking), Techie (machinery), and Solo (combat). The perk tree is branched into melee, blades, handguns, shotguns, rifles, sniper rifles, hacking, two-handed combat, assassination, "cold blood", engineering, and athletics. V must consult a "ripperdoc" to upgrade and purchase cyberware implants; black markets offer military-grade abilities. The rarity of any given equipment is shown by a coloured tier system. V can take cover, aim, run on the ground and walls, jump, double jump, and slide. With arm blades, V may climb walls and, like with other close-combat weapons, deal melee strikes. There are three types of ranged weapons—Power (standard), Tech (which penetrate walls and enemies), and Smart (with homing bullets). These can be customised and modified. Ranged weapons are equipped to ricochet bullets in a target\'s direction and slow them down in bullet time. Four types of damage can be inflicted and resisted—Physical, Thermal, EMP, and Chemical. Weapon use increases accuracy and reloading speed, which are manifested in character animations. Gunsmiths repair and upgrade weapons. The game can be completed without taking a life, with nonlethal options for weapons and cyberware.</item>
        <item>NBA 2K20 is a basketball simulation game which, like the previous games in the series, strives to realistically depict the National Basketball Association (NBA), as well as present improvements over the previous installments. The player mainly plays NBA games with real-life or customized players and teams; games follow the rules and objectives of NBA games. Several game modes are present and many settings can be customized.\nAlong with the current season\'s teams and players, previous games in the series have featured NBA teams from past eras, such as the 1995–96 Chicago Bulls and the 1985–86 Boston Celtics. NBA 2K20 adds six more such teams.\nFor the first time ever in the NBA 2K series, all twelve teams from the WNBA are included. It includes Candace Parker as well as other WNBA all stars.\nA staple of the series, MyCareer, returns as one of the available game modes. MyCareer is a career mode in which the player creates their own customizable basketball player and plays through their basketball career. The mode features a storyline (with the voices of actors including Idris Elba) which plays out as the player competes in games as well as off-court activities. The creation tools have been overhauled.</item>
        <item>FIFA 20 is a football simulation video game published by Electronic Arts as part of the FIFA series. It is the 27th installment in the FIFA series, and was released on 27 September 2019 for Microsoft Windows, PlayStation 4, Xbox One, and Nintendo Switch.\nReal Madrid winger Eden Hazard was named the new cover star of the Regular Edition, with Liverpool defender Virgil van Dijk on the cover of the Champions Edition. Former Juventus and Real Madrid midfielder Zinedine Zidane was later named as the cover star for the Ultimate Edition.\nThe game features VOLTA Football for the first time, a new mode that provides a variance on the traditional 11v11 gameplay and focuses on small-sided street and futsal games. The mode is believed to be focused on the former FIFA Street series.</item>
        <item>The Last of Us is an action-adventure survival horror game played from a third-person perspective. The player traverses across post-apocalyptic environments such as towns, buildings, forest and sewers to advance the story. The player can use firearms, improvised weapons, and stealth to defend against hostile humans and cannibalistic creatures infected by a mutated strain of the Cordyceps fungus. For most of the game, the player takes control of Joel, a man tasked with escorting a young girl, Ellie, across the United States; Ellie and other companions are controlled by the artificial intelligence. The player also controls Ellie throughout the game\'s winter segment.\nIn combat, the player can use long-range weapons, such as rifles, shotguns, and bows, and short-range weapons such as handguns and short-barreled shotguns. The player is able to scavenge limited-use melee weapons, such as pipes and baseball bats, and throw bottles and bricks to distract, stun, or attack enemies. The player can upgrade weapons at workbenches using collected items. Equipment such as health kits, shivs, and Molotov cocktails can be found or crafted using collected items. Attributes such as the health meter and crafting speed can be upgraded by collecting pills and medicinal plants. Health can be recharged through the use of health kits.</item>
        <item>Grand Theft Auto V is an action-adventure game played from either a third-person or first-person perspective. Players complete missions—linear scenarios with set objectives—to progress through the story. Outside of the missions, players may freely roam the open world. Composed of the San Andreas open countryside area, including the fictional Blaine County, and the fictional city of Los Santos, the world is much larger in area than earlier entries in the series. It may be fully explored after the game\'s beginning without restriction, although story progress unlocks more gameplay content.\nThe player character crouched behind a vehicle while in combat. The head-up display elements are visible on-screen. Players may take cover behind objects during firefights to avoid taking damage from enemies. Players use melee attacks, firearms and explosives to fight enemies, and may run, jump, swim or use vehicles to navigate the world. To accommodate the map\'s size, the game introduces vehicle types absent in its predecessor Grand Theft Auto IV, such as fixed-wing aircraft. In combat, auto-aim and a cover system may be used as assistance against enemies. Should players take damage, their health meter will gradually regenerate to its halfway point. Players respawn at hospitals when their health depletes. If players commit crimes, law enforcement agencies may respond as indicated by a "wanted" meter in the head-up display (HUD). Stars displayed on the meter indicate the current wanted level (for example, at the maximum five-star level, police helicopters and SWAT teams swarm to lethally dispatch players). Law enforcement officers will search for players who leave the wanted vicinity. The meter enters a cool-down mode and eventually recedes when players are hidden from the officers\' line of sight that displays on the mini-map.</item>
        <item>The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt is an action role-playing game with a third-person perspective. Players control Geralt of Rivia, a monster hunter known as a Witcher. Geralt walks, runs, rolls and dodges, and (for the first time in the series) jumps, climbs and swims. He has a variety of weapons, including bombs, a crossbow and two swords (one steel and one silver). The steel sword is used primarily to kill humans while the silver sword is more effective against creatures and monsters. Players can draw out, switch and sheathe their swords at will. There are two modes of melee attack; light attacks are fast but weak, and heavy attacks are slow and strong. Players can block and counter enemy attacks with their swords. Swords have limited endurance and require regular repair. In addition to physical attacks, Geralt has five magical signs at his disposal: Aard, Axii, Igni, Yrden and Quen. Aard prompts Geralt to unleash a telekinetic blast, Axii confuses enemies, Igni burns them, Yrden slows them down and Quen offers players a temporary, protective shield. The signs use stamina, and cannot be used indefinitely. Players can use mutagens to increase Geralt\'s magic power. They lose health when attacked by enemies, although wearing armour can help reduce health loss. Health is restored with meditation or consumables, such as food and potions. Players occasionally control Ciri, Geralt\'s adoptive daughter who can teleport short distances. The game has responsive, advanced artificial intelligence (AI) and dynamic environments. The day-night cycle influences some monsters; a werewolf becomes powerful during the night of a full moon. Players can learn about their enemies and prepare for combat by reading the in-game bestiary. When they kill an enemy, they can loot its corpse for valuables. Geralt\'s witcher sense enables players to find objects of interest, including items that can be collected or scavenged. Items are stored in the inventory, which can be expanded by purchasing upgrades. Players can sell items to vendors or use them to craft potions and bombs. They can visit blacksmiths to craft new weapons and armour with what they have gathered. The price of an item and the cost of crafting it depend on a region\'s local economy.</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>
